There's a pretty large variety of tools available for trimming your cat's nails.
The trick is finding something that you're comfortable with and sticking with it.
Some people use regular human nail trimmers.
I find them a little bit uncomfortable because they trim, you know our nails are flat and cats nails go sideways.
So I'm always having a little bit of trouble using them because I feel like I'm using them sideways.
But some people find them very effective.
There are also these very small jawed nail trimmers, which are quite tiny and easy, very easy for some people to use.
They're not personally my favorites, but I know a lot of people enjoy these.
These types of trimmers are my favorite.
They have a little bit of a wider jaw in them.
So a cat with a larger nail, you can actually get the whole nail in there, but still have good control so you're not cutting the nail too short.
And here's a larger brand of nail trimmers that you could use if you have cats and small dogs.
This is a good all purpose nail trimmer that will trim a thicker, harder dog's nail as well as trimming your cats nail.
And it actually has a little guard here that you can put in place, and a lock on it to keep it from getting damaged.
This is called a guillotine type nail trimmer, a lot of people use these for cats and dogs too.
And you can see how as you flex the handle, this blade comes up and trims the nail off.
A lot of people like these.
I find them difficult because I always cut the nails a little bit shorter than I was expecting to cut them.